

Bangalore, KA 560102 | (H) +91 8793651965 | iyogeshjoshi@gmail.com

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Responsible Software Developer proficient in Designing, Developing, and writing efficient and userfriendly software. Passionate and motivated, with a drive for excellence. 8.5+ years of experience in JavaScript and Full-stack development positions. Eager to learn and grow.

### **SKILLS**

- ES6, Javascript, NodeJs
- D3.Js, Highcharts
- HTML5, CSS3
- Debugging, Problem Solving, Critical Thinking User Interfaces and User Experiences
- Agile Methodology, Time Management
- ReactJs, Redux, AngularJs, ExpressJs, SocketIO, NestJs, micro-services
- Google Map SDK/APIs, Firebase toolchain
- macOS, Linux, Windows, Android, iOS

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### AUGUST 2020 - CURRENT

Senior Software Engineer | YARA International | Bengaluru, KA

- Designed and Develop Mobile application using ReactNative, MobX, MobX State Tree, redux and other hybrid technologies
- · Managed new Interns and Trainees, and helped them on-board and learn new technologies and concepts
- · Helped Junior developers and colleagues with their tasks and fix issues when they are stuck
- Managed release of application from internal releases to the play store releases
- Created a micro-service architecture template using NestJs and other required plugins with Backend team
- Designed and developed Backend REST APIs for certain modules
- Developed and managed micro-services on Back-end using NestJs
- · Have added automations, small scripts, and other tools in place to automate daily mundane tasks and to maintain code hygiene and structure
- · Collaborated closely with other teams and Product Owners to complete features and finish the release cycle in all sprints

### JUNE 2015 - AUGUST 2020

Senior Software Engineer (Associate Manager) | Ather Energy Private Ltd. | Bengaluru, KA

- Designed and Develop Software application using ReactJs, Redux and other web technologies for the vehicle which is tightly integrated with other system-level applications.
- Designed and Develop Mobile Application using React Native to sync data across platforms from bike to cloud to the mobile app using Firebase toolchain.
- · Designed and Developed Complete navigation using Vanilla Js/ ReactJS, and Google map js APIs, from scratch on the web platform to be able to use it on our Bike's hardware with limited hardware and memory restrictions.
- Identified performance issues in the application and implemented more optimized components.
- · Guided new joiners and trainees
- · Worked closely with the system team and helped them develop using Go-lang and integrate their app with UI App.
- Developed Coding, Documenting and other version control systems like Git and Gitlab standards and
- Determine system performance standards.
- Automated several everyday mundane tasks for peers and QA to speed up the process using shell scripting or microservices.

• Developed several Software and services within and for other teams to help them analyze, track and solve problems using JavaScript web stack.

#### MAY 2014 - JUNE 2015

Software Artisan | Function Space | Bangalore, Karnataka

- Developed Web applications and tested them for issues.
- Developed, Tested and Maintain online Science forum community platform using PHP, JavaScript, and otherweb stacks technologies.
- Created several applications to help users learn and play at the same time
- Learnise complete learning ecosystem for all the students and teachers, by providing them tools like online IDEs to learn and run on the go.
- Play Physics it is the new way to learn by playing interactive games and interactive quizzes based on science and physics concepts.
- Developed several internal multi-tier dashboards and tools to analyze, track and monitor user's data, behavior, and actions.
- Worked closely with sale and product team to understand user's requirements and with Design and testing team to develop it and test it thoroughly.

### JUNE 2013 - APRIL 2014

Fullstack Software Developer | Avinashi Ventures Pvt Ltd | Surat, GJ

- BizBrain Developed a complete HRMS system using AngularJs, NodeJs, Highcharts, and MongoDB. It
  allows superiors to set and achieve the target for their junior colleagues, if not achieved, s/he can find the
  reason from the dashboard drill-in graphs and charts. It also predicts the future scope of your products
  based on the daily entry by all employees and can help business leaders to take necessary actions
  accordingly.
- Developed and maintained a bulk telemarketing SMS delivery system using NodeJs and AT commands and integrated the same with other applications like BizBrain for delivering and taking system related alerts and inputs respectively.
- Developer mail delivery system to fetch, update and generate reports with charts and deliver it to the respective person automatically using NodeJs, PHP and MongoDB

# **EDUCATION**

2013

Bachelor of Engineering: Computer Engineering

C.K Pithawalla College of Engineering and Technology, Surat, GJ

• GPA 8.05.

## ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Personal hobbies like game development and home automation
- In free time I explore and contribute to Open Source Software